<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ICM | ASGARD Group</title>
    <link>http://asgard-ari.github.io/tag/icm/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://asgard-ari.github.io/tag/icm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>ICM</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>http://asgard-ari.github.io/media/icon_hu_be15dbaf67d618b8.png</url>
      <title>ICM</title>
      <link>http://asgard-ari.github.io/tag/icm/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thermal Instability and Heating Mechanisms in Stratified Atmospheres</title>
      <link>http://asgard-ari.github.io/project/ti-stratified/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://asgard-ari.github.io/project/ti-stratified/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thermal instability (TI) in stratified atmospheres is believed to play a central role in producing the cold gas observed in galaxy clusters’ intracluster medium. A key but poorly understood ingredient is the form of heating that balances cooling: previous work has typically assumed highly idealized, spatially uniform “magic heating” to maintain global thermal equilibrium.&lt;br&gt;
In this project, you will explore TI both theoretically and with numerical simulations, replacing such ad hoc heating prescriptions with more realistic, physically motivated models. By mapping how different heating mechanisms influence condensation, stability criteria, and cold-gas morphology, this work will help build a more robust understanding of how multiphase structure forms in cluster atmospheres.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thermal Instability in Turbulent Multiphase Media</title>
      <link>http://asgard-ari.github.io/project/ti-turb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://asgard-ari.github.io/project/ti-turb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thermal instability plays a key role in shaping the multiphase structure of the ISM, CGM, and ICM, yet its onset within turbulent environments remains poorly understood. In supersonic and subsonic turbulence, compressed regions can cool rapidly and condense, but the precise conditions for when and where this occurs are not well established.&lt;br&gt;
In this project, you will perform turbulent-box simulations and follow the thermodynamic trajectories of gas parcels to determine how turbulence seeds and amplifies thermal instability. The goal is to build a predictive framework connecting local dynamical conditions—compression, cooling times, and turbulent driving—to the formation of cold gas in astrophysical environments.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
