<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Radiative Transfer | ASGARD Group</title>
    <link>http://asgard-ari.github.io/tag/radiative-transfer/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://asgard-ari.github.io/tag/radiative-transfer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Radiative Transfer</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>http://asgard-ari.github.io/media/icon_hu_be15dbaf67d618b8.png</url>
      <title>Radiative Transfer</title>
      <link>http://asgard-ari.github.io/tag/radiative-transfer/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lyman-alpha as a proxy for ionizing photon escape</title>
      <link>http://asgard-ari.github.io/project/lyalyc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://asgard-ari.github.io/project/lyalyc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We know that the Universe turned from neutral to ionized in the so-called &amp;lsquo;Epoch of Reionization&amp;rsquo;. However, we do not know yet how the photons that were responsible for this era escaped their host-galaxies as they can be absorbed by gas already inside the galaxies. Luckily for astrophysics, Lyman-alpha photons are susceptible to the same gas as ionizing photons. In this project, you will run your own radiative transfer simulations to figure out a link between the escape of ionizing and Lyman-alpha photons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a numerical/theoretical thesis with connection to observations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lyman-alpha pumping during the dark ages</title>
      <link>http://asgard-ari.github.io/project/lya-pumping/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://asgard-ari.github.io/project/lya-pumping/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The next generation of telescopes such as the SKA target the 21cm spinflip transition line of neutral hydrogen to map out the Epoch of Reionization (EoR). Ly𝛼 scattering changes the state of hydrogen and thus affects the 21cm signal through the so-called Wouthuysen–Field effect. While this effect is known since a long time, models studying it are very rudimentary. This is because the range of scales (≪pc mean free path of Ly𝛼 photons to &amp;gt;Mpc coherent regions in the EoR) is simply too large to model the effect correctly. In this project, you will run Ly𝛼 radiative transfer simulations of models of galaxies and their surroundings, record the scattering rates and try to find prescriptions to model this effect correctly in larger scale EoR simulations where the gas and radiative transfer around galaxies cannot properly be resolved.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radiation Pressure–Driven Acceleration and Survival of Cold Gas</title>
      <link>http://asgard-ari.github.io/project/cc-radiation-pressure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://asgard-ari.github.io/project/cc-radiation-pressure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Radiation pressure from young stars or AGN is often invoked as a mechanism to accelerate cold gas, yet its role in enabling — or preventing — the long-term survival of this gas remains poorly understood. Competing processes such as shear, instabilities, and radiative cooling complicate the dynamics, and current theories do not reliably predict when radiation pressure helps preserve clouds versus tearing them apart.&lt;br&gt;
In this project, you will conduct radiation–hydrodynamic simulations to study how cold gas clouds respond to radiation pressure under a range of luminosities, optical depths, and ambient conditions. By identifying the regimes in which clouds accelerate, remain coherent, or fragment, the project will shed light on the physical pathways through which radiation pressure shapes multiphase outflows.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The effect of spectral stacking on the information content</title>
      <link>http://asgard-ari.github.io/project/stacking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://asgard-ari.github.io/project/stacking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Electromagnetic radiation is our primary window to observe galaxies and to constrain our theoretical models. In particular, resonant lines such as Lyman-alpha or MgII play a pivotal role in astrophysics as a tool to study low surface brightness region such as the circumgalactic medium. As the detection of a single object is so challenging, it is common practice to perform &amp;ldquo;stacking&amp;rdquo; of individual object, thus beating down the noise and enhancing the signal. However, from a theoretical perspective it is unclear what the stacking analysis does to the spectral shape or the information contained in the data.
In this project, we will systematically explore the information content of individual spectra versus stacks. To do so, you will run radiative transfer simulations and assemble individual synthetic spectra, perform a stacking analysis, and build a fitting pipeline to obtain the information contained in the stacks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
